# Chan Young Park

chanyoun@cs.cmu.edu | https://chan0park.github.io

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research primarily focuses on natural language processing (NLP), AI ethics, and computational social science (CSS). The central aim is to design equitable NLP systems that are adaptable to individuals and groups. Specifically, I enhance NLP system performance and equity by integrating social context into learning procedures. Additionally, I develop frameworks for analyzing biases and fairness in ML and AI systems, as well as bridging the gap between CS and CSS to facilitate the use of cutting-edge AI models in other disciplines, including social science.

# **EDUCATION**

### Carnegie Mellon University

Ph.D., Language Technologies Institute, School of Computer Science Aug 2018 - Present

· Adviser: Prof. Yulia Tsvetkov, GPA: 4.11/4.00

### University of Washington

Visiting Ph.D. Student, Computer Science & Engineering Sep 2021 - Present

### Yonsei University

M.S.,	Computer Science,	School of Integrated Techn	cology	Mar 2016 - May 2018
B.S.,	Computer Science,	School of Integrated Techno	ology	Mar 2013 - Feb 2016

 $\cdot$  Adviser: Prof. Songkuk Kim, M.S. GPA: 4.13/4.00, B.S. GPA: 4.09/4.00

· Magna Cum Laude

# AWARDS

K&L Gates Presidential Fellowship	Oct 2023
Asian Deans' Forum 2023 - The Rising Stars Women in Engineering	Aug 2023
ACL Best Paper Award	July 2023
Wikimedia Foundation Research Award of the Year 2023	May 2023
UChicago Rising Stars in Data Science	Nov 2022
Overseas PhD Scholarship, Korea Foundation of Advanced Studies	Aug 2018 - May 2023
Undergraduate Scholarship, Korea Foundation of Advanced Studies	Mar 2015 - Feb 2016
Excellence Award, Ministry of Science of Korea	May 2015
Full-Ride Scholarship, Yonsei University	Mar 2013 - May 2018

### **PUBLICATIONS**

### **Preprints**

Chan Young Park, Shuyue Stella Li, Hayoung Jung, Svitlana Volkova, Tanushree Mitra, David Jurgens, Yulia Tsvetkov. ValueScope: Unveiling Implicit Norms and Values via Return Potential Model of Social Interactions. In arXiv. arXiv 2024

Shangbin Feng, Taylor Sorensen, Yuhan Liu, Jillian Fisher, <u>Chan Young Park</u>, Yejin Choi, Yulia Tsvetkov. Modular Pluralism: Pluralistic Alignment via Multi-LLM Collaboration. In arXiv. arXiv 2024

Yu Ying Chiu, Liwei Jiang, Maria Antoniak, <u>Chan Young Park</u>, Shuyue Stella Li, Mehar Bhatia, Sahithya Ravi, Yulia Tsvetkov, Vered Shwartz, <u>Yejin Choi. CulturalTeaming</u>: AI-Assisted Interactive Red-Teaming for Challenging LLMs' (Lack of) Multicultural Knowledge. In arXiv. arXiv 2024

Conferences/Journals

Yuhan Liu, Shangbin Feng, Xiaochuang Han, Vidhisha Balachandran, <u>Chan Young Park</u>, Sachin Kumar, Yulia Tsvetkov. What Constitutes a Faithful Summary? Preserving Author Perspectives in News Summarization. In Proceedings of the 2024 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics.

NAACL 2024

Sachin Kumar, Chan Young Park, Yulia Tsvetkov. GEN-Z: Generative Zero-Shot Text Classification with Contextualized Label Descriptions. In *The Twelfth International Conference on Learning Representations*.

ICLR 2024

Chan Young Park\*, Lucille Njoo\*, Octavia Stappart, Marvin Thielk, Yi Chu and Yulia Tsvetkov.

TalkUp: Paving the Way for Understanding Empowering Language. In Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2023.

EMNLP 2023

Jihyung Moon, Dong-Ho Lee, Hyundong Cho, Woojeong Jin, <u>Chan Young Park</u>, Minwoo Kim, Jonathan May, Jay Pujara, and Sungjoon Park. <u>Analyzing Norm Violations in Live-Stream Chat</u>. In *Proceedings of the 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing*. **EMNLP 2023** 

Shangbin Feng, Chan Young Park, Yuhan Liu and Yulia Tsvetkov. From Pretraining Data to Language Models to Downstream Tasks: Tracking the Trails of Political Biases Leading to Unfair NLP Models. In Proceedings of the 61st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. ACL 2023

- · Received ACL Best Paper Award.
- · Media Coverage: "AI language models are rife with different political biases" (MIT Tech Review, 2023), "ChatGPT leans liberal, research shows" (The Washington Post, 2023)

Chan Young Park\*, Julia Mendelsohn\*, Anjalie Field\*, Yulia Tsvetkov. Challenges and Opportunities in Information Manipulation Detection: An Examination of Wartime Russian Media. In Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2022.

EMNLP 2022

Chan Young Park\*, Anjalie Field\*, Antonio Theophilo\*, Jamelle Watson-Daniels, and Yulia Tsvetkov.

An Analysis of Emotions and the Prominence of Positivity in #BlackLivesMatter Tweets. In Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 2022.

PNAS 2022

· Featured: "Analysis of #BlackLivesMatter social media content points to the power of positivity in online activism and large-scale social movements" (UW Allen School News, 2022), "Researchers Study Tweets To Understand Roles of Optimism and Hope in the Black Lives Matter Movement" (CMU SCS News, 2022)

Anjalie Field, <u>Chan Young Park</u>, Kevin Z. Lin, and Yulia Tsvetkov. Controlled Analyses of Social Biases in Wikipedia Bios. In *Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference*, 2022. **WWW 2022** 

· Received Wikimedia Foundation Research Award of the Year 2023. Two papers were chosen among 180+ research papers published on or about Wikimedia projects during 2022.

Chan Young Park, Julia Mendelsohn, Karthik Radhakrishnan, Kinjal Jain, Tushar Kanakagiri, David Jurgens, and Yulia Tsvetkov. Detecting Community Sensitive Norm Violations in Online Conversations. In Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2021. EMNLP 2021

Chan Young Park\*, Jimin Sun\*, Hwijeen Ahn\*, Yulia Tsvetkov, and David R. Mortensen. Ranking Transfer Languages with Pragmatically-Motivated Features for Multilingual Sentiment Analysis. In Proceedings of the Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, 2021.

Chan Young Park\*, Xinru Yan\*, Anjalie Field\*, and Yulia Tsvetkov. Multilingual Contextual Affective Analysis of LGBT People Portrayals in Wikipedia. In Proceedings of International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media, 2021.

ICWSM 2021

· Impact: collaboration with investigative journalists from the Washington Post to collect Chinese social media data and analyze sentiments expressed toward the black population during the pandemic, published as "Video evidence of anti-black discrimination in China over coronavirus fears" (The Washington Post, 2020)

Chan Young Park\*, Hwijeen Ahn\*, Jimin Sun\*, and Jungyun Seo. NLPDove at SemEval-2020 Task 12: Improving Offensive Language Detection with Cross-lingual Transfer. In *Proceedings of the Fourteenth Workshop on Semantic Evaluation*, 2020.

SemEval 2020

Chan Young Park and Yulia Tsvetkov. Learning to generate word-and phrase-embeddings for efficient phrase-based neural machine translation. In *Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Neural Generation and Translation*, 2019.

WNGT 2019

### Industry Experience

#### Facebook AI

Research Intern May 2021 - Sep 2021

· Developed models for *personalized sentiment classification*, specifically explored various pre-training objectives and methodologies to train transformer-based personalized language models. Location: Seattle, WA, Team: AI Integrity, Mentor: Hao Ma, Additional Mentors: Madian Khabsa, Simon Wang, Yuxiao Dong

#### Adobe Research

Research Intern May 2019 - Aug 2019

· Developed *language generation models* for procedural texts such as instructions and recipes. Location: San Jose, CA, Team: NLP, Mentor: Doo Soon Kim

Research Intern Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

· Developed text segmentation models. Location: San Jose, CA, Team: NLP, Mentor: Seokhwan Kim

#### Naver Clova AI

Research Intern

Jul 2017 - Nov 2017

· Conducted research on dialog state tracking and developed a tool to visualize dialog response templates. Location: Seoul, Korea, Team: Dialog Systems, Mentor: Kyungduk Kim

# TEACHING

Guest lecture for Natural Language Processing

Spring 2022

· University of Washington, Gave a lecture on text summarization

Guest lecture for Algorithms for NLP

Fall 2021

· Carnegie Mellon University, Gave a lecture on text summarization

Lecture for Low-Resource NLP Bootcamp

Fall 2020

· Carnegie Mellon University, Led a hands-on learning session for Multilingual NLP

TA for Algorithms for NLP

Fall 2019, Spring 2020

· Carnegie Mellon University, Developed assignments and quizzes, delivered lectures and recitations, and mentored student research projects.

TA for Theory of Algorithm

Fall 2016, Fall 2017

· Yonsei University, Developed homework assignments

# INVITED TALKS

#### Measuring Social Biases Using Language Technologies

University of Arizona, Ethics Colloquium, Oct 2023

Socioculturally Aware Language Technologies

KAIST School of AI, Aug 2023

#### Socioculturally Aware Language Technologies

Aptima, Aug 2023

#### Multilingual Contextual Affective Analysis of LGBT People Portrayals in Wikipedia

Wikimedia Research Showcase, Jun 2023

### Socioculturally Aware Language Technologies

KAIST School of Computing, Jun 2023

# Challenges and Opportunities in Opinion Manipulation Detection

University of Chicago, Nov 2022

# Challenges and Opportunities in Opinion Manipulation Detection

Text as Data (TADA) Conference, Oct 2022

### Recent Advances in NLP and AI Ethics

Hyundai Vision Conference, Aug 2022

## SERVICE

# Mentoring

· Farhan Samir, PhD Student, UBC	2023
· Stella Li, PhD Student, UW	2023
· Hayoung Jung, MS Student, UW	2023
· Lucille Njoo, PhD Student, UW	2023
· CMU K-12 Summit on AI for Social Good Symposium	2022
· CMU Graduate Application Support program	2020, 2021
· Hwijeen Ahn, CMU, Visiting MS Student $\rightarrow$ CMU LTI	2020
· Jimin Sun, CMU, Visiting MS Student	2020
· Xinru Yan, MS student, CMU	2020

### Area Chairing

 $\cdot$  EMNLP 2023: Ethics track

### Workshop Organizing

· EMNLP 2024: Customizable NLP: Progress and Challenges in Customizing NLP for a Domain, Application, Group, or Individual

### Reviewing

- · ACL 2023
- · EMNLP 2020, 2021, 2022, 2023
- · CoNLL 2021, 2022
- · NAACL SRW 2020, 2021
- · NLP4PI Workshop 2021, 2022

### SKILLS

- · Computer-related: Python, C++, C, Java, React, Django, AWS, SQL, R, MATLAB
- · Natural Language: English, Korean